<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<setting>
<careers>
<career><name>Doctor</name>
<stats>Start with Tough -1, Sharp +1, Steady +0, then increase your choice by 1.</stats>
<description>You make a living fixing—or at least ameliorating—the physical ills of life. Name a specialty and describe your practice. Lifestyle: Well-off</description>
<recovery><basicmovename>Recovery</basicmovename>
<movebody>When you receive appropriate medical treatment (GM's call), recover Suffer Harm. When you build a basic human relationship with someone (their player's call), recover one of Take a Risk, Keep it Together, or Study, your choice.</movebody></recovery>
<moveinstructions>Choose two:</moveinstructions>
<moves><move><movename>Forensics</movename>
<movebody>When you study a dead body, ask the GM what killed it. If the death was mundane, the GM will describe the circumstances. If the death was supernatural, the GM will tell you the nearest mundane cause, plus what doesn’t fit that cause.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Medic</movename>
<movebody>When you give a dying person your undivided attention you buy them time. They won’t die for at least a few moments and the GM will tell you what you can do to keep them alive longer—maybe even avoid death entirely.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Family Doctor</movename>
<movebody>Off the top of your head you know the medical history of everyone in town.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>First Aid</movename>
<movebody>When you provide immediate medical aid to someone who’s suffered harm, they roll with your Sharp instead of their Tough.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Miracle Worker</movename>
<movebody>When you treat someone with a permanent condition, ask the GM how the condition could be removed. They will always give you a way (though it may take some work).</movebody></move></moves>
<history><basicmovename>History</basicmovename>
<event>I saved _______'s life, they know they're in good hands with me. They take +1 to Keep it Together in your presence. Others you save enjoy the same benefit.</event>
<event>_______ has shown an interest in my work which I appreciate. They get +1 Sharp in your presence. Others who study under you enjoy the same benefit.</event>
<event>I trust _______ to hear me out when the work is too much. They take +1 when aiding you. Others you open up to enjoy the same benefit.</event></history>
</career>
<career><name>Reporter</name>
<stats>Start with Tough +0, Sharp +1, Steady -1, then increase your choice by 1.</stats>
<description>You write stories, maybe with an investigative bent, for a periodical—name it, describe its topic(s), and choose a news beat (crime, politics, or high society maybe). Lifestyle: middle class</description>
<recovery><basicmovename>Recovery</basicmovename>
<movebody>When you receive appropriate medical treatment (GM's call), recover Suffer Harm. When you build a basic human relationship with someone (their player's call), recover one of Take a Risk, Keep it Together, or Study, your choice.</movebody></recovery>
<moveinstructions>Choose two:</moveinstructions>
<moves><move><movename>Tell</movename>
<movebody>When you talk to someone and can carefully study them you can ask the GM if they’re lying about any given statement, as often as you please. The GM will answer truthfully.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Muckraker</movename>
<movebody>You’re known for bringing down people (deserving or not) with your stories. If you report on something with the barest of evidence you can be sure the proper authorities (local police, most likely) will get involved as soon as your story hits. This may not be a good thing, but at least they can’t kill you without somebody asking questions, right?</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Camera Man</movename>
<movebody>You’re used to taking your own photos. Unless you’re physically denied a working camera, you always have photographic evidence of every place you’ve been. Not that everyone will believe it.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Connected</movename>
<movebody>You always know who’s in the know. When you seek information, you can always ask the GM “who might know more about this?” The GM will answer truthfully, including where that person can usually be found.</movebody></move></moves>
<history><basicmovename>History</basicmovename>
<event>I filed a story on _____ and it made them look good—they owe me. They take +1 to aid you. Others you report on enjoy the same benefit.</event>
<event>_____ helped me out with a particularly tough story, we worked well together. They take +1 to aid you. Others who help you investigate enjoy the same benefit.</event>
<event>I always give _____ a copy of my notes, just in case someone comes after me. They take +1 to aid you. Others who keep your secrets enjoy the same benefits.</event></history>
</career>
<career><name>Librarian</name>
<stats>Start with Tough -1, Sharp +1, Steady +0, then increase your choice by 1.</stats>
<description>You take care of a large collection of books, either publicly owned or part of a university collection. You track and maintain the books, promote reading, and aid the interested in finding what they need. Lifestyle: middle class</description>
<recovery><basicmovename>Recovery</basicmovename>
<movebody>When you receive appropriate medical treatment (GM's call), recover Suffer Harm. When you build a basic human relationship with someone (their player's call), recover one of Take a Risk, Keep it Together, or Study, your choice.</movebody></recovery>
<moveinstructions>Choose two:</moveinstructions>
<moves><move><movename>Everybody Reads</movename>
<movebody>When you consult library records on a person you can always piece together some meaning from even the most random selection of books—the GM will tell you what goal that person is working towards (anything from "losing weight" to "raising the dead," depending on the person).</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Special Collection</movename>
<movebody>Your collection contains books on a particularly notable topic, some of which can be found nowhere else. Name the topic. You can be sure that anyone looking for information on that will come to your library. With enough time, you can find anything known (and written) on the topic.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Grimoir</movename>
<movebody>Some of the books in your collection contain spells and you know which they are. (If your collection isn’t special, this means other libraries have similar spells, which sounds bad.) The GM will give you two or more spells as benefits of your job. With time spent in research you can probably find more.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Bookworm</movename>
<movebody>When you have peace and solitude to read you recover Keep it Together or Study, your choice.</movebody></move></moves>
<history><basicmovename>History</basicmovename>
<event>_____ donated something unique to my collection. You get +1 to aid them. Others who give generously to the library enjoy the same benefit.</event>
<event>I helped _____ find something they thought was lost. You gain a +2 bonus (instead of +1) when they aid you in Studying. Others who help you solve a mystery gain the same benefit.</event>
<event>_____ and I share a taste in literature, we discuss our reads on a regular basis. When you recover with them you recover two moves instead of one. Others who talk books with you enjoy the same benefit.</event></history>
</career>
<career><name>Detective</name>
<stats>Start with Tough +0, Sharp +1, Steady +0, then increase your choice by 1.</stats>
<description>You investigate crimes. Maybe you have an assignment—homicide, larceny, or the like—but depending on the available cops you may get assigned anything. You find facts, make a case, and take it to the powers of justice. Lifestyle: middle class</description>
<recovery><basicmovename>Recovery</basicmovename>
<movebody>When you receive appropriate medical treatment (GM's call), recover Suffer Harm. When you build a basic human relationship with someone (their player's call), recover one of Take a Risk, Keep it Together, or Study, your choice.</movebody></recovery>
<moveinstructions>Choose two:</moveinstructions>
<moves><move><movename>Gut Feeling</movename>
<movebody>When you study someone closely, you can ask the GM (or player, for PCs) what crimes they’ve committed recently. They will answer truthfully, but offer no proof.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Connected</movename>
<movebody>When you need to find something out, tell the GM what you want to know. They’ll give you a way to find out involving people (informants, prisoners, officials).</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Brawler</movename>
<movebody>When you take a risk in personal combat (fists, bats, knives, or the like) you treat a roll of 6- as a 7–9 instead.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Self-Medicating</movename>
<movebody>When you drink yourself to sleep, choose one of your breaks: it’s under control, for now. Of course drinking and hangovers may mean taking risks for normal tasks.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Undercover</movename>
<movebody>Name an organization you have in-depth knowledge of: the GM will tell you how you can gain access, and what act you’ll have to keep up to do so.</movebody></move></moves>
<history><basicmovename>History</basicmovename>
<event>They liked _____ for a crime, but I found the real perp. They take +1 to aid you. Others whom you save from the long arm of the law enjoy the same benefit.</event>
<event>_____ was a victim of a crime, I got to the bottom of it. Ask their player any one question, they must answer truthfully. Anyone you investigate gets the same treatment.</event>
<event>_____ and I drink at the same bar, we drown our woes together and toast the good times. When you share a night of drinking with them you recover two moves. Others who become you drinking buddies enjoy the same benefit.</event></history>
</career>
<career><name>Artist</name>
<stats>Start with Tough -1, Sharp +1, Steady +0, then increase your choice by 1.</stats>
<description>You make visual art of some sort—paintings, drawings, or sculpture, maybe. Describe your style and the type of people who pay you for your work. Lifestyle: struggling</description>
<recovery><basicmovename>Recovery</basicmovename>
<movebody>When you receive appropriate medical treatment (GM's call), recover Suffer Harm. When you build a basic human relationship with someone (their player's call), recover one of Take a Risk, Keep it Together, or Study, your choice.</movebody></recovery>
<moveinstructions>Choose two:</moveinstructions>
<moves><move><movename>Notable</movename>
<movebody>Something in your art has gotten widespread attention. Increase your lifestyle to well-off (as the doctor).</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Insight</movename>
<movebody>When you create art directly related to something supernatural you personally experienced, the GM will tell you what the work requires of you. If you do it, the GM will reward you with some insight into the supernatural (most likely related to the event that inspired you, but not always).</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Crazy Like a Fox</movename>
<movebody>While you have at least one break that isn’t under control, you have Sharp +3 instead of your normal Sharp.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>And I Feel Fine</movename>
<movebody>When you have at least one break that isn’t under control, you get +1 Steady (to a maximum of +3).</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Empathy</movename>
<movebody>When you create art based on a supernatural event you experienced, anyone who views that art will immediately experience exactly what you felt in that moment (fear, despair, or otherwise).</movebody></move></moves>
<history><basicmovename>History</basicmovename>
<event>_____ has been the subject of my art before. Ask their player any one question, they must answer truthfully. Anyone else who sits for your art gets the same treatment.</event>
<event>I owe _____ for helping me through some hard times. Take +1 to aid them. Others who come to your aid enjoy the same benefit.</event>
<event>_____ can pull me out of myself when I get too involved in my work. When you build a connection with them choose a break—it's now under control. Others who break through your shell enjoy the same benefit.</event></history>
</career>
<career><name>Priest</name>
<stats>Start with Tough +0, Sharp +0, Steady +2, then increase your choice by 1.</stats>
<description>You represent the religion of your choice within the community. Your job is less theology and more pastoral: helping those in need, bringing together the community, and spreading the word. Lifestyle: middle class</description>
<recovery><basicmovename>Recovery</basicmovename>
<movebody>When you receive appropriate medical treatment (GM's call), recover Suffer Harm. When you build a basic human relationship with someone (their player's call), recover one of Take a Risk, Keep it Together, or Study, your choice.</movebody></recovery>
<moveinstructions>Choose two:</moveinstructions>
<moves><move><movename>Rites</movename>
<movebody>So long as you fulfill the regular offices of your religion (usually some sort of daily services, plus larger weekly events) your breaks are under control.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>The Good Book</movename>
<movebody>When you spend time in quiet meditation with your scriptures, the GM will give you some insight into the situation at hand that is comforting.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Reliquary</movename>
<movebody>Your house of worship has something of supernatural power within it. The GM will tell you what it is, and at least some of what it does.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Minister</movename>
<movebody>When another player comes to you for advice, tell them what they should do. If they follow your advice, they take +1 forward to do it.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Superstition</movename>
<movebody>You have a love for the esoteric and apocryphal. When you encounter the supernatural the GM will tell you something about it that you would have learned from the fringes of your religion.</movebody></move></moves>
<history><basicmovename>History</basicmovename>
<event>_____ is a member of my flock. So long as they attend regularly choose one of their breaks: it's under control. Other members of your congregation enjoy the same benefit.</event>
<event>_____ helps me in my duties. They take +1 to aid you. Others who take an active role in the church gain the same benefit.</event>
<event>When my faith falters I come to _____ for understanding and advice. When acting on their advice you take +1 forward.</event></history>
</career>
<career><name>Mechanic</name>
<stats>Start with Tough +1, Sharp +1, Steady +0, then increase your choice by 1.</stats>
<description>You take care of cars. If it’s broke, you can fix it. You have a few regular clients who come to you for maintenance, but most of your work is when something just isn’t working. Lifestyle: middle class</description>
<recovery><basicmovename>Recovery</basicmovename>
<movebody>When you receive appropriate medical treatment (GM's call), recover Suffer Harm. When you build a basic human relationship with someone (their player's call), recover one of Take a Risk, Keep it Together, or Study, your choice.</movebody></recovery>
<moveinstructions>Choose two:</moveinstructions>
<moves><move><movename>Fix-It</movename>
<movebody>When you encounter a mechanical device (or simple machine) that’s not working, you may ask the GM how it could be fixed. The GM will tell you the easiest way.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>The Only Shop In Town</movename>
<movebody>You’re the only car shop in town. Whenever you interact with somebody who might reasonably have used your services int the past, the GM will tell you some secret about them you learned while fixing their car.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Thugs</movename>
<movebody>The folks you work with trust you implicitly. They’ll do anything up to minor crimes so long as you can show them how it would really help you out.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Improvised</movename>
<movebody>You can build just about anything using the tools in your workshop. Tell the GM what machine you want to build. They’ll say “yes, you can build that, but…” and then one or more of these:
<ul><li>It’ll be limited in some particular way</li>
<li>You’ll need some extra tools or materials to do it</li>
<li>It’ll fall apart pretty quick</li>
<li>It’ll be dangerous to use</li></ul></movebody></move></moves>
<history><basicmovename>History</basicmovename>
<event>_____ helped me get started in this business, I owe them. Take +1 to aid them. Others who invest in your business get the same benefit.</event>
<event>I fixed something for _____ when they really needed it. They take +1 to aid you. Others who you do a favor for enjoy the same benefit.</event>
<event>_____ and I go way back. You always know when something is wrong with them no matter what separates you.</event></history>
</career>
<career><name>Professor</name>
<stats>Start with Tough -1, Sharp +2, Steady +0, then increase your choice by 1.</stats>
<description>You teach and research, pursuing a clearer knowledge of some academic topic. Name the institution you work for and the field you work in. Lifestyle: middle class</description>
<recovery><basicmovename>Recovery</basicmovename>
<movebody>When you receive appropriate medical treatment (GM's call), recover Suffer Harm. When you build a basic human relationship with someone (their player's call), recover one of Take a Risk, Keep it Together, or Study, your choice.</movebody></recovery>
<moveinstructions>Choose two:</moveinstructions>
<moves><move><movename>Research</movename>
<movebody>You're on to something cutting edge and beyond the normal. When you want to do something seemingly impossible related to your field, the GM will tell you the cost or requirement. Do it and the laws of reality are yours to bend.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Knowledgeable</movename>
<movebody>When you encounter something important (your call) that falls within your field, you may ask the GM any one question about it, they’ll answer honestly.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Mentor</movename>
<movebody>When another player comes to you for advice, tell them what they should do. If they follow your advice, they take +1 forward to do it.</movebody></move>
<move><movename>Renown</movename>
<movebody>You are known as an expert in your field, and therefore experts in other fields as well. When you want to know more about an academic topic, tell the GM what you want to know, they’ll tell you who you know that could tell you, and how you might get a hold of them.</movebody></move></moves>
<history><basicmovename>History</basicmovename>
<event>I taught _____ and found them a notable student. They gain +1 Sharp when in your presence. Others who study under you enjoy the same benefit.</event>
<event>_____ has an active amateur interest in my field, which I encourage. They take +1 to aid you.</event>
<event>I speak with _____ on matters beyond my field, a welcome distraction. When you unwind with them you recover two moves instead of one.</event></history>
</career>
</careers>
<setups>
<setup><title>The Mansion On The Hill</title>
<description>I don’t think anybody ever really expected the old man to die. He was a fixture here, as much as you can be a fixture when you rarely leave your house. Odd was the kind word for him, though plenty of people had others. Now that he’s gone I guess the old place is being opened up, and I hear what’s in there is pretty strange. Must be valuable to someone too, since everybody seems to want to claim it as their own.</description>
<options><option><question>What strange collection did the old man leave behind?</question>
<ul><li>Books, many handwritten in various hands, some unorthodoxly bound.</li>
<li>Specimens, in unlabled jars, lovingly displayed. Some of them don’t look like anything natural.</li>
<li>Idols and totems, in a variety of tiny sanctuaries, many with fresh offerings.</li>
<li>Keys, every one ornate, some impractical, but nary a lock in sight.</li></ul></option>
<option><question>How did the old man die?</question>
<ul><li>Of an apparent overdose</li>
<li>Drained of all blood, but without a cut</li>
<li>Cut up cleanly with one piece in each room, except for the eyeballs nobody found</li>
<li>Nobody knows, since he’s only presumed dead</li></ul></option></options>
<connections><instructions>Each player chooses one and fills in their character's name:</instructions>
<connection>_______ has a claim to something valuable and strange in the old man's belongings, but the claim is disputed.</connection>
<connection>A local business is trying to buy up the mansion for some odd purpose, but _______ has been fighting them.</connection></connections></setup>
</setups>
</setting>